Samuel Flewwelling Papers
Litchfield Historical Society
Samuel Flewwelling Papers
1799-1868
Litchfield Historical Society 7 South Street, P.O. Box 385 Litchfield, CT, 6759 URL: http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon Email: archivist@litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org Phone: 860-567-4501 Fax: 860-567-3565
Flewwelling, Samuel, 1774 or 5-1849
0.83
The papers of New York City banker and businessman Samuel Flewwelling (1774 or 5-1849) primarily relating to property held by his wife, Julia Elvira Canfield Flewwelling (1791-1868), and him in the Western Reserve, later Ohio. Following Samuel's death, the properties were managed by William Mackay (1795-1873), a New York City businessman and the husband of Caroline Emma Canfield Mackay. The collections includes indentures, agreements, leases, deeds, statements and accounts, and correspondence.
2010-96-0
Biographical Note
Samuel Flewwelling was born in 1774 or 1775, a son of Abel Flewwelling and Abigail Fowler Flewwelling of Newburgh, N.Y. The Flewwellings moved to New Brunswick during or shortly after the American Revolution. Samuel became associated with William Rhinelander in New York in 1796 and joined the Manhattan Bank in 1801 as bookkeeper. He was promoted to more responsible positions, becoming cashier of the Poughkeepsie branch in 1809. In 1810, he returned to the main office to become cashier until 1817, when he became cashier of the City Bank. He was the cashier of the Delaware and Hudson Canal Company from 1825 until 1829, when he became cashier of the National Bank in New York. Flewwelling maintained residences in New York City and Nyack, N.Y. He retired in 1840 and died in 1849. Samuel Flewwelling married Julia Elvira Canfield, a daughter of Judson Canfield and Mabel Ruggles Canfield. Samuel and Julia Flewwelling had no children.
Scope and Contents
The papers of New York City banker and businessman Samuel Flewwelling (1774 or 5-1849) primarily relating to property held by his wife, Julia Elvira Canfield Flewwelling (1791-1868), and him in the Western Reserve, later Ohio. Following Samuel's death, the properties were managed by William Mackay (1795-1873), a New York City businessman and the husband of Caroline Emma Canfield Mackay. The collections includes indentures, agreements, leases, deeds, statements and accounts, and correspondence.
Samuel Flewwelling was born in 1774 or 1775, a son of Abel Flewwelling and Abigail Fowler Flewwelling of Newburgh, N.Y. The Flewwellings moved to New Brunswick during or shortly after the American Revolution. Samuel became associated with William Rhinelander in New York in 1796 and joined the Manhattan Bank in 1801 as bookkeeper. He was promoted to more responsible positions, becoming cashier of the Poughkeepsie branch in 1809. In 1810, he returned to the main office to become cashier until 1817, when he became cashier of the City Bank. He was the cashier of the Delaware and Hudson Canal Company from 1825 until 1829, when he became cashier of the National Bank in New York. Flewwelling maintained residences in New York City and Nyack, N.Y. He retired in 1840 and died in 1849.
Samuel Flewwelling married Julia Elvira Canfield, a daughter of Judson Canfield and Mabel Ruggles Canfield. Samuel and Julia Flewwelling had no children. Julia's siblings were Henry J. Canfield (1789-1856) of Canfield, Ohio; Elizabeth Hannah Canfield Tallmadge (1793-1878); and Caroline Emma Canfield Mackay (1798-1872).
The papers are arranged chronologically in one series and consist mostly of documents concerning the conveyance land in the Western Reserve. The earliest document outlines the partitioning of land Judson Canfield and others purchased from the Connecticut Land Co. in 1799. Flewwelling acquired land from Canfield as early as 1815. Some of the later sales were among members of Flewwelling's family, including his father-in-law Judson Canfield, his brother-in-law Henry J. Canfield, and his brother- and sister-in-law Frederick Augustus Tallmadge and Elizabeth Canfield Tallmadge. Flewwelling provided mortgages to some of the purchasers of land, and the agreements contained in the papers spell out the payment terms.
For many years, Royal Millard served as Flewwelling's agent in Ohio, and the collection includes many of his letters reporting on the buying and selling of properties and the collection of funds. After Millard died in 1854, Henry Canfield and William H. Canfield, a nephew of Judson Canfield, served as agents in Ohio, and their letters are also represented in the collection.
Following Flewwelling's death in 1849, his brother-in-law William Mackay, a New York City businessman whose father William and brother Robert Mackay were wealthy Boston merchants, managed the Ohio lands for Julia Canfield Flewwelling. It appears that by the time of Mrs. Flewwelling's death in 1868 all of her and her late husband's Ohio land holdings may have been sold.
Of particular interest in the papers are several documents that summarize Flewwelling's property holdings and detail the contracts and deeds he held.
Arrangement of Materials
This collection is arranged in one series:
1. Papers, 1799-1868
Related Materials
Judson Canfield Papers (1985-70-0)
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Connecticut Land Company
Family Name:
Canfield family
Genre/Form of Material:
Business records; Correspondence; Deeds; Financial records; Leases; Legal documents; Mortgages
Geographic Name:
Western Reserve (Ohio)
Topical Term:
Flewwelling, Julia Canfield; Mackay, William; Millard, Royal
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Litchfield Historical Society from Carroll Swope on 03/01/2010.
Other Information
This collection was processed with support from the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR) and the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC).
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Papers, 1799-1868
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Indenture between David Waterman, Nathaniel Church, James Johnston, Elijah Wadsworth, Samuel Canfield, Judson Canfield, proprietors of Township Number One in the the third range in the Connecticut Reserve for the purpose of making a partition of the same between said proprietors, 1799 Jan 12 (Folder 1)
  - [Deed, fragment], Canfield, Judson; Waterman, David; Johnston, James; Church, Nathaniel; Wolcott, Frederick; Wadsworth, Elijah; and Canfield, Samuel, circa 1799 (Folder 2)
  - Deed, Calhoun, Joseph and Calhoun, Sarah to Canfield, Judson, 1814 Oct 1 (Folder 3)
    Property in Cleveland, Ohio.
  - Deed, Canfield, Judson to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1815 Jan 14 (Folder 4)
    Property in Canfield, Ohio.
  - Deed, Grainger, Gideon and Granger, Mindwell to Canfield, Judson, 1815 Aug 2 (Folder 5)
  - Deed, Ruggles, Herman and wife to Ruggles, Oliver, 1816 Jan 2 (Folder 6)
    Property in Newton, Ohio.
  - Deed, Johnston, James to Canfield, Judson, 1816 Feb 4 (Folder 7)
  - Deed, Canfield, Judson and Canfield, Mabel Ruggles to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1816 Jun 16 (Folder 8)
    Property in Cuyahoga County, Ohio.
  - Deed, Canfield, Judson and Canfield, Mabel Ruggles to Ruggles, Thomas Colden and Ruggles, Julia Flewwelling, 1816 Jun 21 (Folder 9)
  - Deed, Canfield, Judson and Canfield, Mabel Ruggles to Ruggles, Thomas Colden and Ruggles, Julia Flewwelling, 1816 Jun 22 (Folder 10)
  - Deed, Canfield, Judson and Canfield, Mabel Ruggles to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1817 Jul 5 (Folder 11)
  - Deed, Canfield, Judson and Canfield, Mabel Ruggles to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1817 Dec 8 (Folder 12)
    Property in Trumbull County, Ohio.
  - Deed, Canfield, Judson and Canfield, Mabel Ruggles to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1817 Dec 15 (Folder 13)
    Property in Portage County and Medina, Ohio.
  - Deed, Canfield, Judson to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1817 Dec 17 (Folder 14)
  - Deed, Wright, Amaziah andWright, Maria Ruggles to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1818 Jun 7 (Folder 15)
    Property in Medina County, Ohio.
  - Deed [fragment], Canfield, Judson and Canfield, Mabel Ruggles to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1818 Jun 24 (Folder 16)
  - Promissory note, Tallmadge, Frederick to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1819 Sep 20 (Folder 17)
  - Deed, Gifford, James and Gifford, Susanah to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1820 Jan 24 (Folder 18)
  - Deed, McMullen, John to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1820 Sep 4 (Folder 19)
  - Deed, Plimpton, David and Plimpton, Rosealana to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1823 Sep 26 (Folder 20)
  - Property owned by Samuel Flewwelling, circa 1825 (Folder 21)
    Detailed, annotated inventory, including land, stocks, and other investments.
  - Order, Tallmadge, Frederick to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1826 Feb 1 (Folder 22)
  - Deed, Flewwelling,, Samuel and Flewwelling, Julia Canfield to Canfield, Judson, 1826 May 2 (Folder 23)
    Property in Johnston, Ohio.
  - Receipt, Allen, John to Tallmadge, Frederick for rent on No. 36 Vesey St., New York, 1829 Mar 9 (Folder 24)
  - Deed, Canfield, Herman and Canfield, Fetia Bostwick to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1829 Jun 28 (Folder 25)
  - Deed, Canfield, Henry and Canfield, Sally Ferriss to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1829 Aug 17 (Folder 26)
    Property in Rockport, Ohio.
  - Order, Tallmadge, Frederick to Holden, Horace, 1830 Jan 4 (Folder 27)
  - Notes, Canfield, Judson to Buell, Almira, 1830 Apr 30 (Folder 28)
    2 items. Receipts for payments made 1832-1834 including those by Samuel Flewwelling on reverse.
  - A statement of deeds from Judson Canfield to Samuel Flewwelling and from Joseph Smith to Samuel Flewwelling: also from Herman Canfield to Samuel Flewwelling, 1830 May 2 (Folder 29)
  - Receipt, Holden, Horace from Tallmadge, Frederick, 1830 Aug 6 (Folder 30)
  - Order, Tallamadge, Frederick to Holden, Horace, 1830 Aug 16 (Folder 31)
  - Order, Flewwelling, Samuel to bearer, 1830 Aug 17 (Folder 32)
  - Tallmadge, Frederick to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1830 Aug 17 (Folder 33)
    Asks for a short-term loan of $86 to resolve a matter with Mr. Allen regarding the possession of Tallmadge's house.
  - Order, Tallmadge, Frederick to Holden, Horace, 1831 May 11 (Folder 34)
  - Order, Tallmadge, Frederick to Holden, Horace, 1831 Jul 7 (Folder 35)
  - Deed, State of Connecticut to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1832 Aug 2 (Folder 36)
    Quit claim to property in Ohio for the consideration of one dollar.
  - Deed, Lane, John to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1832 Aug 7 (Folder 37)
  - Deed, Canfield, Herman and Canfield, Fetia Bostwick to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1832 Dec 6 (Folder 38)
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel and Lane, Levi, 1833 Mar 31 (Folder 39)
    For the purchase of property in Ohio.
  - Deed, Canfield, Herman and Canfield, Fetia Bostwick to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1833 Jul 14 (Folder 40)
  - Flewwelling, Samuel to Hine, Philip, 1833 Sep 5 (Folder 41)
    Inquires about a matter involving the Delaware and Hudson Canal Company.
  - Deed, Canfield, Herman and Canfield, Sally Ferriss to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1833 Dec 19 (Folder 42)
  - Lease, Flewwelling, Samuel to Canfield, Henry, 1834 Apr 1 (Folder 43)
    Farm in Canfield, Ohio.
  - Deed, Lane, William R. and Flewwelling, Samuel, 1834 Jun 10 (Folder 44)
  - Deed, Flewwelling, Samuel and Flewwelling, Julia Canfield to Barber, Lawrence and Barber, George, 1834 Oct 10 (Folder 45)
  - Contracts for lands in Ohio, 1835-1848 (Folder 46)
    Summary document listing dates and values of land holdings.
  - Statement of account, Canfield, Judson to Lane, William, 1835 Mar 9 (Folder 47)
  - Deed, Kidney, James and Kidney, Rebecca to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1835 Mar 31 (Folder 48)
    Property in Rockport.
  - Deed, Canfield, Henry and Canfield, Sally Ferriss to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1835 May 5 (Folder 49)
  - Flewwelling, Julia Canfield to Lane, William, 1835 May 20 (Folder 50)
    Requests a power of attorney for Samuel Flewwelling to sell property in Cleveland, Ohio.
  - Deed, Lane, William and Lane, Pamela Hubbell to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1835 May 26 (Folder 51)
  - Received of Henry Canfield, contracts for collection by William Canfield, 1835 Aug 8 (Folder 52)
    William H. Canfield (1806-1874), the son of Judson Canfield's brother Herman Canfield and Fetia Bostwick Canfield, was a lawyer in Medina, Ohio, who later moved to Kansas.
  - Receipt, Flewwelling, Samuel from Canfield, Henry, 1835 Aug 17 (Folder 53)
  - Receipt, Flewwelling, Samuel from Canfield, Henry, 1935 Aug 18 (Folder 54)
  - Lease, Flewwelling, Samuel and Flewwelling, Julia Canfield to Canfield, Henry, 1835 Aug 25 (Folder 55)
  - Leases assigned to Clark, Edmund, 1835 Aug 25 (Folder 56)
  - Receipt, Flewwelling, Samuel from Canfield, Henry; receipt, Millard, Royal from Flewwelling, Samuel, 1835 Aug 25 (Folder 57)
  - Monies received and expended by Judson Canfield when in Ohio in 1836, 1836 Aug (Folder 58)
  - Account, Millard, Royal, 1839-1846 (Folder 59)
  - Canfield, William to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1839 Mar 30 (Folder 60)
    Discusses his business dealings in Medina, Ohio and provides a statement of his account with Flewwelling, 1836-1839.
  - Particulars of money collected by Royal Millard since 1835, 1839 Nov 1 (Folder 61)
  - Notes regarding Kidney and Barnum mortgages, circa 1840 (Folder 62)
  - Deed, Townsend, Caleb and Townsend, Nancy to Munson, Laura, 1841 Jan 23 (Folder 63)
    Property in New Rochelle, N.Y.
  - Deed, Lane, William and Lane, Pamela Hubbell to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1841 Feb 1 (Folder 64)
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel and Morris, John, 1841 Feb 23 (Folder 65)
    For purchase of property in Rockport, Ohio.
  - Deed, Flewwelling, Samuel and Flewwelling, Julia Canfield to Tallmadge, Frederick, 1841 Jul 1 (Folder 66)
  - Deed, Tallmadge, Frederick and Tallmadge, Elizabeth Canfield to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1841 Jul 2 (Folder 67)
  - Mortgage, Munson, Laura to Benedict, Abner, 1841 Oct (Folder 68)
  - Bond, Munson, Laura to Benedict, Abner, 1841 Oct 3 (Folder 69)
  - Note, King, Brown to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1841 Nov 26 (Folder 70)
  - Deed [unsigned], Flewwelling, Samuel and Flewwelling, Julia Canfield to Canfield, Henry, 1842 (Folder 71)
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel and Graves, Elisha, 1842 Dec 21 (Folder 72)
    For the purchase of property in Rockport, Ohio.
  - Memorandum of notes and balances due May 1st 1835, 1844 May 10 (Folder 73)
    Detailed listing of notes and contacts owed to Flewwelling, with additional notes and calculations up through May 10, 1844. A lengthy note in what appears to be Judson Canfield's hand discusses future prices and makes recommendations on when to sell land in Canfield, Newton, Section 23, and Rockport.
  - Statement of payments made on contract to Samuel Flewwelling Esq. and William H. Canfield, 1844 Jun 11 (Folder 74)
    For property in Medina, Ohio.
  - Agreement between Hilliard, Richard; Hays, William; and Flewwelling, Samuel, 1844 Aug 31 (Folder 75)
    For the purchase of property in Cleveland, Ohio.
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel and Coon, Prosser, 1844 Nov 4 (Folder 76)
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel and Beall, Walter, 1844 Dec 23 (Folder 77)
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel and Lease, Joseph, 1845 Jan 14 (Folder 78)
  - Deed, Executors of Tallman, Michael to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1846 May 28 (Folder 79)
    Property in Nyack, N.Y.
  - Deed, De Pew, Wilmpe to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1846 Sep 30 (Folder 80)
  - Deed, De Pew, Wilmpe to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1846 Sep 30 (Folder 81)
  - Assignment of mortgage, Benedict, Abner to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1846 Dec 12 (Folder 82)
    Mortgage of Laura Munson.
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel; Flewwelling, Julia Canfield; and McKanna, Patrick, 1847 Apr 10 (Folder 83)
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel and Coe, Martilla, 1847 Oct 6 (Folder 84)
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel and Coon, Henry, 1847 Oct 6 (Folder 85)
  - Deed, Tallman, Ann to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1847 Nov 23 (Folder 86)
  - Deed, Tallman, Ann to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1847 Nov 23 (Folder 87)
  - Statement of property belonging to Samuel Flewwelling, 1847 Dec 20 (Folder 88)
    Detailed inventory of holdings and their values, including stocks, land, and other property. Total amount is $58,600.
  - Account, Canfield, Henry, 1847 Dec 28 (Folder 89)
    Summary of activities, 1835-1847.
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Samuel; Warren, John; and Warren, Thomas, 1848 Mar 27 (Folder 90)
  - Agreement between Wilde, Henry and Flewwelling, Samuel, 1848 Jun 24 (Folder 91)
  - Agreement between Hall, Joseph; Hall, Sarah; and Flewwelling, Samuel, 1848 Aug 18 (Folder 92)
  - Correspondence, 1849 Feb-Apr (Folder 93)
    - Ruggles, Charles to [Flewwelling, Samuel], 1849 Feb 28 (Folder 93)
      Regarding two plats of land.
    - Millard, Royal to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1849 Mar 7 (Folder 93)
      Encloses his account and a draft and acknowledges deeds received.
    - Millard, Royal to Flewwelling, Samuel, 1849 Apr 16 (Folder 93)
      Received Flewwelling's receipt and is enclosing a draft.
  - Correspondence, 1849 Jul (Folder 94)
    - Allen, John to Tallmadge, Frederick, 1849 Jul 4 (Folder 94)
      Allen expresses his regrets regarding Flewwelling's death. He reports that he has a claim in Flewwelling's favor and will again contact Tallmadge to find out who the executors are.
    - Tallmadge, Frederick S. to Mackay, William, 1949 Jul 9 (Folder 94)
      Reports on advice provided by Mr. Noyes about notifying heirs and placing advertisements.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1849 Jul 14 (Folder 94)
      Acknowledges the news of Flewwelling's death and discusses business Flewwelling left to him.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1849 Jul 18 (Folder 94)
      Reports on property sold to Hilliard and Clark and asks for instructions on matters relating to Flewwelling's affairs and estate.
    - Reeve, Saleh to Mackay, William, 1849 Jul 18 (Folder 94)
      Encloses a letter received from D. Tooker listing the children of Charlotte Purdy, sister of Flewwelling.
  - Correspondence, 1849 Aug-Oct (Folder 95)
    - Allen, John to Mackay, William, 1849 Aug 4 (Folder 95)
      Mr. Clark is eager to settle his affairs. He paid an inflated price for his land. Allen discusses what Allen may be willing to pay to settle and provides a recommended course of action.
    - Harding, James to Mackay, William, 1849 Aug 4 (Folder 95)
      Harding reports from St. John, Canada, on Flewwelling's relatives there.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1849 Aug 31 (Folder 95)
      Encloses a draft and reports that there are frequent applications to purchase Mackay's lands. Also, some purchasers of land have failed to pay.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1849 Sep 25 (Folder 95)
      Provides a copy of the power of attorney given Millard by Flewwelling. Reports on mortgages of Kidney, Barnum, and Cary.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1849 Oct 29 (Folder 95)
      Although he does not have authority, he has been collecting funds on Flewwelling's lands. Inquires about paying taxes due in December.
  - Correspondence, 1850 Jan (Folder 96)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1850 Jan 14 (Folder 96)
      Discusses the Cary, Prosser Coon, and Barnum mortgages. Millard has paid taxes on all lands, including those of Mr. Tallmadge. A draft is enclosed. Discusses inquiries about purchasing lands and prices Henry Canfield has set.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1850 Jan 17 (Folder 96)
      Encloses a draft.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1850 Jan 26 (Folder 96)
      Proposes to sell to Henry Drier and William Drier the only 50 acres of land belonging to the estate of Flewwelling still unsold.
  - Deed [wrapper], [Estate of Flewwelling, Samuel] to Coon, Prosser, 1850 Jun 28 (Folder 97)
    Property in Section No. 9.
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Julia Canfield; Drier, Henry; and Drier, William, 1850 Feb 13 (Folder 98)
  - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1850 Mar 5 (Folder 99)
    Encloses a draft, the Drier and Drier contract, and his current account. He has the opportunity to make a small sale. Discusses Mason's loans and deeds. Believes that the law requires wills to be deposited in county where land lies.
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Julia Canfield and Barnum, George, 1850 Jul 1 (Folder 100)
  - Correspondence, 1850 Nov-Dec (Folder 101)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1850 Nov 2 (Folder 101)
      Discusses land sales relating to Brainard, Colbrenn, and Finney. Encloses two deeds belonging to Caroline Mackay.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1850 Dec 7 (Folder 101)
      Encloses a draft. He has been delayed due to ill health. Reports on taxes paid for Julia Canfield Flewwelling, William Mackay trust deeds, Caroline Canfield Mackay, and Henry Canfield. Reports on Henry Canfield's advice about selling land. Mackay's reply, dated Dec 20, 1850 is on the last page, in which he acknowledges Millard's letter and responds to Millard's proposals.
  - Correspondence, 1851 Feb-Mar (Folder 102)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1851 Feb 4 (Folder 102)
      Encloses a draft. Reports on a German man, who has not purchased land as expected. There are no other opportunities to sell land and no inquiries. Offers his opinion about selling two 100-acre tracts held by Julia Canfield Flewwelling.
    - Allen, John to Mackay, William, 1851 Feb 6 (Folder 102)
      Discusses the claim due the estate of Flewwelling in which he is involved. Briefly mentions political climate in Washington, D.C.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1851 Mar 28 (Folder 102)
      Encloses a draft. His health is better. The German has not taken the contract and Millard will look for other purchasers.
  - Agreement between Sexton, Albe; French, Collins; and Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1851 Apr 10 (Folder 103)
  - Agreement between Sexton, Albe; French, Collins; and Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1851 Apr 10 (Folder 104)
  - Correspondence, 1851 Apr-May (Folder 105)
    - Clark, Edmund to Mackay, William, 1851 Apr 14 (Folder 105)
      Inquires about the chain of title to lot No. 79 in Cleveland, Ohio. Discusses the possibility of reducing his debt to as small an amount now due Mr. Hilliard.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1851 Apr 29 (Folder 105)
      Received W. D. Beall's deed. Millard's health is poor, but will comply with Mackay's requests as he can.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1851 May 7 (Folder 105)
      Encloses a statement of account and a draft. He has reviewed his accounts and had found no mistakes, believing the error to which Mackay referred is an omission concerning postage.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1851 May 7 (Folder 105)
      A detailed listing of notes and agreements in Millard's possession belonging to the estate of Samuel Flewwelling. Millard advises that his health is poor and there may be miscalculations.
  - Correspondence, 1851 Jun-Nov (Folder 106)
    - Clark, Edmund to Mackay, William, 1851 Jul 24 (Folder 106)
      He asks for a fair deduction on the balance due, and if so, he will discharge the debt in full.
    - Canfield, Henry to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1851 Aug 6 (Folder 106)
      He is glad Julia's health is better. The notes she should send him are those of George Jones. Discusses Nelson Jones notes and hopes he can draw against those notes and what he is due from books sold from Mr. Mackay. Provides an accounting of funds received and used in the building his house.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1851 Aug 14 (Folder 106)
      Encloses a draft. Reports on a rail road laid leading from Cleveland to Toledo that passes through Mrs. Tallmadge's or Mackay's land in Rockford. Discusses the implications of the right of way and what the rail company will pay. Corrects a mistake he made in his previous account.